Jean-Charles Quillet

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · FUNCTIONAL PROGRAMMING

13, rue du clos romain, 35120 Dol-de-Bretagne, FRANCE

🛮 (+33) 6-65-13-50-75 | 🗷 jeancharles.quillet@gmail.com | 🔏 jeancharles.quillet.org | 🖸 jecaro | 🛅 jeancharlesquillet

Summary.

I am a software developer with a large experience in very diverse fields. I have worked as a backend developer, have written desktop applications, simulation software as well as network servers.

I have had the chance to work with low-level object-oriented programming such as C++ which I have used professionally for more than ten years, and also with very high-level functional programming languages such as Haskell. These different approaches give me a good comprehension of the mechanisms at work in software development, always driven by the goal of developing correct, safe, and robust software.

Skills.

Main skills Architecture and software design

Functional and object oriented programming Networking / Linux systems administration Geographic Information Systems

Geometry and 3D rendering

Programming Haskell, Rust, Elm, C/C++, Python, Bash **Development tools** Nix, Make, Git, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker

Scientific tools Matlab, Octave, gnuplot

Operating systems Windows, Linux (NixOS, ArchLinux, Ubuntu, CentOS, Debian)

Languages French: mother tongue, English: fluent, Spanish: beginner

Experience ____

Secucloud Hamburg, Germany / Remote

Since 11/2020

CLOUD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Develop cloud network security software
- Work in an international team
- Technical environment: Linux, Haskell, JavaScript, nix, Ansible, Clickhouse

Epitech Rennes, France

FUNCTIONAL PROGRAMMING TEACHER

09/2021 - 06/2023 (part time)

- $\bullet \quad \text{Supported the students with their Haskell projects (Arithmetic expression evaluator, List interpretor, image compression algorithm ...)}\\$
- Technical environment: Linux, Haskell, nix

Scalian Rennes, France

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER FOR A SUBCONTRACTOR COMPANY

• Developed simulation software in the department Simulation, HPC and Virtual Reality

- Architecture and technical lead
- Technical documentation writing
- Clients: french MoD, ONERA, CEA, CNES, IRSN
- Technical environment: Windows/Linux, C++, Python, Matlab, Qt, openscenegraph, gdal

LaBRI Analysis and indexing video team (University lab)

Bordeaux, France 07/2006 - 08/2006

04/2007 - 11/2020

RESEARCH ENGINEER

- Prepared the video indexing contests TRECVID and ARGOS
- System administration
- Technical environment: Linux, C/C++, XML, Perl, Bash

INRIA IPARLA team (French IT lab)

Bordeaux, France

RESEARCH ENGINEER

- Visualization of city models on mobile devices though non-photorealistic rendering
- Wrote and presented a scientific paper to the Web3D 2006 conference in Washington
- Technical environment: Linux, Windows, Windows Mobile, C/C++, Bash, Perl, VRML97, X3D

09/2004 - 04/2006

1

KeyghostChristchurch, New-Zealand

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 04/2003 - 12/2003

- Developed security software
- Technical environment: Windows, Delphi, C/C++, Octave

VisualpixBordeaux, France

INTERNSHIP FOLLOWED BY A SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONTRACT

- Improved a video compression codec
- Technical environment: Linux, C

Glisshouse Marseille, France

BACKEND DEVELOPER, SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

07/2000 - 03/2001

04/2002 - 12/2002

- Web: Maintained an online shop, developed a CMS
- System administration: Installed, setup and maintained the LAN (router, DNS, firewall, proxy, backup management, file server, print server)
- Technical environment: Linux, Php, MySQL, Apache, Samba, cron

Education

| 2001 - 2002 | DESS Multimedia and Information Technology, | Bordeaux university |
|-------------|---|-----------------------------------|
| | image synthesis and analysis, 3D geometry and rendering, sound, video | |
| 1999 - 2000 | Master in computer science, image synthesis and analysis | Poitiers university |
| 1998 - 1999 | B.S. in computer science | Limoges university |
| 1996 - 1997 | DEUG computer science and mathematics | Limoges university |
| 1995 - 1996 | Baccalauréat Science | Lycée Jean Giraudoux, Châteauroux |

Extracurricular Activity _____

Sports Rock climbing, bike commuting, surf, trekking

Culture Literature (classical, travel, adventure), cinema, attending rock concerts, guitar playing

Community commitments Member of the direction comity of the rock climbing club of Rennes (2012 to 2016)

Volunteered at concert venues of Rennes: Antipode (2011 to 2015), le Jardin Moderne (2009 to 2010)

Volunteered to the music festivals Epipapu (2009, 2010) and la Route du Rock (2008 - 2018)

Travel New-Zealand, Australia, USA, Canada, Malaysia, Bali, Bolivia, Iceland, Norway, Scotland, Faroe Islands